Guide to the Niels A. Douwes Dekker papers, [ca. 1900]-1950, 1944-1946 (bulk)
Dekker, Niels A. Douwes papers, [ca. 1900]-1950, 1944-1946 (bulk)
- Series I. Photographs
  - Revolution
    - Daily life/evacuees/internees
      - 7049-7088 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - 7089-7128 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - 7129-7168 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - 7169-7208 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - 7209-7248 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - 7249-7288 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - 7289-7328 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - 7329-7368 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - 7369-7408 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - 7409-7448 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - 7449-7488 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - 7489-7529 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - 7530-7559 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - 7560-7584 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - 7585-7614 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - 7666-7675 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - 7676-7685 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - 7686-7695 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - 7696-7705 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - 7706-7715 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - 7716-7725 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - 7726-7735 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - 7736-7745 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - 7746-7755 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - 7756-7764 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - 7765-7774 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - 7775-7781 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - 7782-7787 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - 7666-7675 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - 7676-7685 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - 7686-7695 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - 7696-7705 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - 7706-7715 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - 7716-7725 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - 7726-7735 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - 7736-7746 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - 7747-7756 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - 7757-7766 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - 7767-7776 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - 7777-7787 (negatives) (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - 7585-7588 (smallpox vaccination) (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - 7788-7797 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - 7798-7806 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - 7807-7816 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 7817-7820 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - 7821-7834 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - 7835-7847 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - 7848-7861 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - 7862-7872 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - 7873-7882 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - 7883-7892 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - 7893-7902 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - 7903-7912 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - 7913-7922 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - 7923-7928 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - 7929-7930 (Box 14, Folder 36)
      - 7931-7940 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - 7941-7950 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - 7951-7960 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - 7961-7973 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - 7974-8005 (photograph "album") (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - 8006-8011 (negatives) (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Demonstrations/parades
      - 7615-7644 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - 7645-7652, 7640-7652 (negatives) (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 7653-7665 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Eastern Indonesia
      - 8012-8060 (photograph "album": Ambon, Banda, Kai after allied liberation) (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - 8061-8075 (photograph "album") (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - 8076 (sugar cane stalks [?] added to dirt to enrich the soil?) (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - 8077-8105, 8106 (negative) (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - 8107-8115 (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - 8116-8205 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - 8206-8217 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - 8218-8226 (crowning of the Raja of Goa, 1947) (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - 8227-8236 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - 8232-8239 (negatives) (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - 8237-8239, 8218, 8220, 8218, 8220, 8227-8231 (negatives) (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - 8240-8244 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - 8245-8254 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - 8255-8261 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - 8262-8267 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - 8268-8279 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - 8280, 8281 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Graffiti/propaganda
      - 8282-8291 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - 8292-8301 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - 8302-8311 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - 8312-8321 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - 8322-8331 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - 8332-8341 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - 8342-8351 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - 8352-8361 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - 8362-8371 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - 8372-8374 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - 8282-8291 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - 8292-8301 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - 8302-8312 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - 8313-8323 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - 8324-8334 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - 8335-8345, 8370, 8373, 8374 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Japanese occupation
      - 8374-8383 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - 8384-8393 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - 8394-8403 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - 8404-8413 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - 8414-8428, unmatched negatives (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - 8424-8430 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - 8431-8438 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - 8439-8448 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - 8449-8458 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - 8459-8468 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - 8469-8478 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - 8479-8486 (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - 8427-8430 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - 8431-8437 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - 8438-8447 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - 8448-8457 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - 8458-8467 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Officers/headquarters
      - 8488-8496 (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - 8488-8492 (negatives) (Box 27, Folder 35)
      - 8498-8509 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Military/political documents related to box 32 (negatives not numbered) (Box 27, Folder 37-39)
      - Photographs: notables, maps, and miscellaneous (Box 28)
      - Glass negatives and some photographs (artwork and government propaganda) (Box 29)
      - Negatives and some photographs for The Dead Still Live (Box 30)
      - Negatives (oversize) for The Dead Still Live (Box 31)
      - Material originally with negatives for The Dead Still Live (Box 31)
      - Index to negatives and photographs in boxes 30-31 (Box 31)
- Series II. Manuscript materials
  - Military/political documents
    - Indonesian (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Javanese (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Sudanese (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Dutch, 1946-47 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Dutch, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - English (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Documents relating to Chinese situation in Indonesia
    - Indonesian (Box 32, Folder 9-10)
    - English, Chinese (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Dutch (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - News reports
    - Regeerings Voorlichtings-Dienst, 1947-49 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Views of U.S. Voters on the Netherlands and Indonesia," Feltus Associates, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "An Analysis of American News Coverage...On the Dutch Indonesian Situation," Feltus Associates, ca. 1948 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Typescripts of articles for Het Dagblad, 1949 (Dutch, English) (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Federalism
    - Dutch (Box 32, Folder 17-21)
    - English (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Privately printed report on nationalistic activities in Java, 1946--Dutch (Part I) (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Privately printed report on nationalistic activities in Java, 1946--Dutch (Part II) (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Ministry of Information correspondence, charts, and reports re: civil service positions in W. Java, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence of the Red Cross re: evacuees, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence of Trade Commission of the Netherlands Indies, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Letter re: "What the Republic of Indonesia Requires from India" (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence concerning the Prince Bernhard Fund, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous--Dutch (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Clippings: John Lie incident (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Clippings (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Clippings: Japanese propaganda (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Death, death ritual, and magic: typescripts, notes, and clippings (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Military/political documents--defense maps of Palembang, Sumatra (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and broadside re: Indonesian independence celebration, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and newspapers (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - The Dead Still Live--maps (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Clippings re: death, death ritual, and magic (Box 33, Folder 5-9)
    - Manuscript (volume): Hun Doden Leven (Box 34)
    - Manuscript (volume): De Doden Leven (Box 34)
    - The Dead Still Live--notes, typescripts, and clippings (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - The Dead Still Live--notes, clippings, and contact prints re: Bali (see maps) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - The Dead Still Live--typescripts re: Tengger (see maps) (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - The Dead Still Live--notes, typescripts, and maps re: Toradja (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - The Dead Still Live--miscellaneous clippings and typescripts (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - The Dead Still Live--miscellaneous clippings (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Cut-outs and other photos for Tanah Air Kita, The Dead Still Live, and other publications being prepared in 1951 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Photography: Lists of photos and miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous typescripts (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - The Dead Still Live cover design (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Series III. Duplicate photographs
  - Sumatra (Box 36)
  - Borneo (Box 37)
  - Celebes (Box 38)
  - Maluku (Box 39)
  - Nusa Tenggara (Box 40)
  - Java (Box 41)
  - Death ritual (Box 42)
  - Revolution (Box 43)
  - Portraits, miscellany (Box 44)